NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services Files. 6174/003
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  March 22, 1982. Memo re budget economies, including appointment of committee to study possible savings in mailings, with attached internal memo by Department of Labor re travel reimbursement for state employees (for comparison with less-restrictive NYSUT policy), March 17, 1982; memo re telephone equipment proposal, March 12, 1982
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  February 22, 1982. Memo re proposed staff assignments; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1982 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  February 1, 1982. Memo announcing staff meeting; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  July 14, 1988. New Local Presidents Conference program of events, "Democracy in Education/Education for Democracy," July 18-21, 1988; memo announcing staff meeting
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  June 6, 1988. Agenda for staff meeting; agenda for local presidents conference; fact sheet on Division of Research and Educational Services; checklist of NYSUT services
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  February 3, 1988. Agenda for administrative committee meeting, May 31, 1988; memo from Committee on Office Closings re inclement weather policy, November 20, 1987
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 23)
  November 5, 1985. Agenda of Administrative Committee meeting, September 24, 1985; NYSUT Information Bulletin with results of survey of presidents of elementary and secondary school locals, 1983-84; Executive Committee meeting agenda, October 17, 1985; minutes, September 12; NYSUT Employee Assistance Program concept paper for women's demonstration project
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 24)
  June 3, 1985. Local Leaders' Guide to NYSUT Research and Educational programs and services, 1983-84
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 25)
  May 20, 1985. Job description for director of research; memo re New Presidents' Conference; minutes of Executive Committee, March 14 and April 25; memo from NYSUT Vice President Antonia Cortese re proposal for Assertive Discipline course for Effective Teaching Program, May 15, 1985; recommendations of NYSUT Occupational Education Committee, with letter from Cortese noting referral to Executive Committee, May 14, 1985; membership analysis (total active, retired, etc.) for April 30, 1984 – April 30, 1985
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 26)
  April 30, 1985. Handwritten notes; memo re health insurance coverage in retirement
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 27)
  c. 1986. Handwritten notes; memo to Santelli re procedures for making small purchases
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 28)
  October 1, 1984. Minutes of Executive Committee, with comments by Al Shanker and other members, September 27, 1984; memo to Administrative Committee re Legislative Department programs and goals for 1985; memo re goals of Finance and Administration Department for 1984-85; goals for Office of General Counsel, New York City and Albany; goals of Executive Office, from Tom Hobart; goals for Division of Field Services
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 29)
  June 18, 1984. List of regional workshops for Division of Field Services; list of new NYSUT information bulletins; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 30)
  June 4, 1984. Memos re areas of responsibility for Division of Research and Educational Services
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 31)
  April 16, 1984. Agenda for Administrative Committee meeting; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 32)
  February 13, 1984. Agenda for Administrative Committee meeting; memo re revised travel request procedures
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 33)
  May 21, 1984. Minutes of professional staff meeting; proposed Commissioner's Regulations re teacher resource computer training centers; memo to school superintendents re BOCES program for summer school; list of areas of responsibility for Division of Research and Educational Services; memo re building security
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 34)
  April 15, 1985. Printout of comments re local assessment of NYSUT services
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 35)
  April 1, 1985. Printout of comments re local assessment of NYSUT services; memo re Sen. John Marchi's tuition tax credit bill, with text of legislation; NYSUT legislative memorandum, "Opposes," re Marchi bill; agenda of meeting of local site coordinators, and list of questions to consider, March 29-30; correspondence re proposed State Education Department review of master's programs in elementary education
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 36)
  March 4, 1985. Paper prepared for the AFT Executive Council, "Peer Review in the Context of Teacher Professionalism," by Linda Darling-Hammond, January 1985; agenda for Administrative Committee meeting, February 20, 1985; agenda for Board of Directors meeting, February 22-23, 1985; agenda for Coordinators' meeting, February 19, 1985
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 37)
  July 1, 1985. Agendas for NYSUT Board of Directors meeting, coordinators' meeting
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 38)
  June 17, 1985. Letter to Al Shanker from the Public Policy Institute re directory listing, May 22, 1985; list of NYSUT-sponsored workshops; NYSUT memo re proposed legislation requiring certification of teachers, and memo in support by NYC Office of the Mayor; text of Assembly bill
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 39)
  October 5, 1981. Minutes of Professional Staff meeting of 9/28/91
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 40)
  September 28, 1981. Minutes of Professional Staff meeting of 9/28/91; memos re Human Relations Follow-Up Program; memo re staff training program on educational issues; agenda for staff training program of 11/9; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 41)
  June 22, 1981. Memos re using a common membership figure; affirmative action for minorities and handicapped in summer employment; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 42)
  May 18, 1981. Resolutions re student discipline, teacher centers, education and the revitalization of America, quality education; program for regional conference on student discipline, cosponsored by NYSUT, State Education Department, NYS School Boards Association, School Administrators Association of New York State, and PTA, May 29, 1981
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 43)
  March 16, 1981. Memo re tuition tax credit project; review of proposed resolutions; schedule for South African visitor; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 44)
  March 2, 1981. Outline re tuition tax credit project
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 45)
  January 26, 1981. Memo re staff training meeting
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 46)
  December 15, 1980. Agenda for staff meeting; preliminary report for discussion at Data Probe '80 National Symposium
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 47)
  November 17, 1980. Memo from NYSUT president Tom Hobart requesting that copies of all correspondence to locals be sent to his office for the central file; memo re telephone equipment changes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 48)
  December 1, 1980. Handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 49)
  October 6, 1980. Staff meeting agenda; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 50)
  September 18, 1980. Routine memos; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 51)
  June 23, 1980. Routine memos; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 52)
  May 12, 1980. Memo re budget/staff requests
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 53)
  April 28, 1980. Routine memos; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meetings, 1973-1977 (Box 51, Folder 54)
  Minutes; description of R+ES services
- Research & Educational Services (R+ES) Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 55)
  February 9, 1987. Meeting request forms for Civil and Human Rights Committee, Occupational Education Committee, Special Education Committee, and Task Force on the Hurried Child
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 56)
  March 9, 1987. NYSUT Local Leaders' Guide to Research & Educational Issues 1985-86; program agenda for New Local Presidents Conference, July 13-16, 1987; information sheet, Helping the Beginning Teacher; Executive Committee meeting agenda, March 6, 1987; Administrative Committee meeting agenda, February 28, 1987
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 57)
  March 25, 1981. Handwritten notes; newspaper clippings
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 58)
  April 13, 1987. Suggested questions for R&ES retreat
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 59)
  May 11, 1987. Meeting agenda; list of consensus points
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 60)
  July 13, 1987. Meeting agenda; memo re planning for 1987-89, sample worksheets
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 61)
  June 1, 1987. Priorities and implementation issues
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 62)
  June 15, 1987. List of consensus points; memo
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 63)
  August 17, 1987. Agenda
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 64)
  September 24, 1987. Agenda; memo re Training Committee; Staff Development Sub-committee report
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 65)
  October 13, 1987. Agenda; memo re new overtime/part-time report of hours; forms
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 66)
  October 27, 1987. Agenda; confidential memo re interim report of the Commissioner's Task Force on the State Education Reorganization Department; questionnaire for presidents of elementary and secondary teacher locals 1985-86; Executive Committee meeting agenda; memo re retirement of Vito DeLeonardis, executive director of Field and Legal Services; memo re proposed constitutional amendments; NYSUT Building Corporation resolutions
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 67)
  November 24, 1987. Agenda; goal worksheets
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 68)
  December 14, 1987. Agenda of Board of Directors meeting
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 69)
  November 24, 1986. Regional Staff Directors meeting agenda; Executive Committee meeting agenda; monthly report
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 70)
  September 22, 1986. List of NYSUT-sponsored workshops for 1986-87 school year; handwritten notes
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 71)
  June 3, 1986. Administrative Committee meeting agenda; list of Field Services upcoming regional events; copy of flyer for course, "How to Keep Your Company Union-Free," with cover memo recommending boycott of creator, Vencopass Business Systems; Bureau of National Affairs report noting Supreme Court's striking down special layoff protection for blacks
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 72)
  June 26, 1986. Booklet, NYSUT Programs, Services, Publications; related publicity materials; Regional Staff Directors meeting agenda
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 73)
  May 12, 1986. Agenda; list of monthly "Inside Your Schools" program themes
- Executive Committee Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 74)
  May 15, 1986. Executive Committee agenda and minutes of May 15 meeting; memo recommending budget increase and related financial spreadsheets; memo re selection of candidates for Regents; memo re agency fee reduction; letter correcting error in statement of dues for retirees; State Education Department press releases announcing James E. Allen Award to Albert Shanker and approval of new Excellence in Teaching Program; related legislative bulletin from New York State School Boards Association
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 75)
  January 6, 1986. Memo re modification of (employee) absence reporting procedure; list of topics for 1984-85 information bulletins
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 76)
  March 3, 1986. Agenda
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 77)
  November 4, 1987. Agenda; management information workshop calendar
- R+ES Staff Meeting, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 78)
  April 28, 1986. Agenda; Report on Actions of the 1986 Representative Assembly; notes of staff meeting; memo re PEF payments; handwritten notes
- R+ES 1982-83 Budget See also: 1978-79 Budget (NYSUT), 1982-1983 (Box 51, Folder 79)
  Budget comparisons for special projects over several years; equipment purchase requests
- 1982-83 Budget Projections, 1982-1983 (Box 51, Folder 80)
  Program spreadsheets
- 1980-81 Budget, 1980-1981 (Box 51, Folder 81)
  Memo re areas in which spending was far more than what had been budgeted; memos re rationale for new budget items; budgets for various departments
- 1981-82 Budget (folder 1), 1981-1982 (Box 51, Folder 82)
  Bound copy, NYSUT Proposed Budget 1981-82; confidential memo from Charles Santelli to NYSUT Vice President Toni Cortese re severe understaffing in Division of Research and Educational Services; handwritten draft of letter
- 1981-82 Budget (folder 2), 1981-1982 (Box 51, Folder 83)
  Analysis of daily activities of several individuals for work year June 1980 through May 1981; budget request worksheets for several departments
- 1981-82 Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 51, Folder 84)
  6 magnetic cards. 3.25" x 7.5" cards for use with an IBM Selectric typewriter. These cards were made by the National Blank Book Company.
- Research and Education Services – Staffing Needs (1979-80 Budget Requests), 1978 (Box 51, Folder 85)
  Memo to NYSUT officers re staffing needs at Division of Research and Educational Services; similar memos and spreadsheets
- Research Requests, 1988-1990 (Box 51, Folder 86)
  Memos, handwritten notes re a variety of issues
- Research Requests, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Research Requests, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 2)
- Research Requests, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  Handwritten notes, phone message slips, and fax sheets requesting answers to a variety of questions re regulations; some written answers from NYSUT staff assistant Phil Ellis
- Research Requests, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  Request forms re policy questions
- Requests, 1973-1979 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  Requests for clarification of policy re teacher competency and other issues
- RESTRUCTURING / Shared Decision Making / Professional Decision Making / School Improvement See also: Education Reform/Restructuring See also: Effective Schools See also: Effective Teaching Program PTA
- NYSUT School Restructuring Project (Phase 1), 1980 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  Agenda and worksheets for training session; mission statements from school districts in support of shared decision making
- School Restructuring, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  NYSUT documents: "Successful Schools Are Student Centered: Restructuring Education," describing goals of shared decision making; "Three Missing Keys to Restructuring Schools"; cover memo from NYSUT associates Don Mesibov to Pat Flynn (?) for fact sheet, "Successful Processes Require Design Principles and Key Commitments"
- Restructuring Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  Handwritten memo from Pat Flynn (?) to Don Mesibov re project support, December 12, 1993, referring to several printed articles, some included
- Restructuring Conference, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  NYSUT document for conference, outlining aims of program, "Meeting and Exceeding the Mandates of the Compact for the Purpose of restructuring our Schools through Shared decision making," July 13, 14, 1992; evaluation form showing assessment by participants
- Restructuring Progress (Pat Flynn), 1993 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  Memo from Pat Flynn to NYSUT research director Charles Santelli and Harry Lampman accounting for time on restructuring project, April 8; memo from Flynn outlining schedule for completing involvement on project, June 1
- Restructuring "Field Testing" Scope Descriptions, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  Brief descriptions of NYSUT's restructuring/shared decision making project: "NYSUT's Pilot Project: A Policy Direction for Restructuring" and "Proposal Regarding the Development and Field Testing of a Curriculum for Focusing Building-Site Committees' Restructuring Efforts on Standards, Assessment and Curriculum in Accordance with NYSUT Policy," by Pat Flynn and Don Mesibov, November 1, 1992
- Restructuring Criteria, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  Memos from Harry Lampman to restructuring steering committee discussing selection criteria for project sites
- Restructuring Guidelines, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  Memo outlining administrative procedures for requests for training materials, scheduling meetings, and related matters
- Restructuring Higher Ed., 1992 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  Memo from Pat Flynn re providing resources about how school restructuring might apply to higher education
- Restructuring (Patsy Clark), 1993 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  Memo from Pat Flynn recommending compensation for consultant Patsy Clark; memo to Clark re procedures for payment
- Restructuring Project Overview, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  Fact sheet outlining three phases of development and training for shared decisionmaking/restructuring project; descriptive brochure; memo outlining resources to make the program work; paper presenting case for restructuring, "Improving Public Elementary, Middle, and Secondary Education Results in the 1990s"
- Restructuring Project Materials, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  Training worksheets
- Restructuring Project Inquiries, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  Cost estimate for implementation of two-year restructuring project per school; letter from Sachem (Long Island) Central Teachers Association, requesting more information; memo listing participating districts
- Restructuring Phase 1 Changes, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  Comments re steps needed to implement plan
- Restructuring Phase 2 Meeting, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  Memos re next steps
- Restructuring/Shared Decisionmaking (SDM) Plans, 1991-1992 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  Mission statements from school districts around the state, endorsing plan
- Restructuring Policy, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 22)
  Draft policy statement, "NYSUT's Pilot Project: A Policy Direction for Restructuring," and cover memo to NYSUT Vice President Antonia Cortese; newspaper clipping from Education Week discussing project
- Restructuring – Project Subcommittee on Proposals, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 23)
  Memo from Harry Lampman summarizing meeting re level of service to be provided to school districts for restructuring plan
- Restructuring – Contract Status Report, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 24)
  August 11, 1993. Report on involvement with participating school districts, mostly terminal
- Restructuring Status Reports, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 25)
  Memo from Don Mesibov re status of restructuring program by district, lack of informed support by boards of education, summary of overall progress of program
- Restructuring – Video Tapes, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 26)
  Memos re use of staff training tapes
- Restructuring – Restructuring – Summer Work Sessions, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 27)
  Memo from Pat Flynn re schedule of training sessions, completing involvement on project; draft school restructuring plan and training exercises
- Restructuring Newsletter, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 28)
  Two issues of program newsletter
- Restructuring – The Forum, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 29)
  Workshop training materials: FORUM Guidance, Post-FORUM References, Workbook for Using the FORUM Guidance to Create a School Restructuring Plan
- Restructuring Manual, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 30)
  Reference Manual for Student Centered Education; pages for presentation as overhead transparencies
- Restructuring – 1A Contract, 1992-1993 (Box 52, Folder 31)
  c. 1992-1993. Contract agreements with school districts for NYSUT-supplied training assistance in school restructuring plans; list of contract expiration dates with pilot school districts
- Restructuring – 1B Consultants, 1991-1992 (Box 52, Folder 32)
  Memos re facilitators' honoraria; non-staff consultants
- Restructuring – Project Review Meeting 1993 (Box 52, Folder 33)
  Outline of NYSUT school restructuring plan, "A Proposal in 4 Parts"
- Restructuring Steering Committee, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 34)
  November 2, 1992. Summary of meeting
- Restructuring Sub Steering Committee, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 35)
  December 4, 1992. Considerations generated by 3/4/92 training of consultant/trainers re FORUM training materials
- Restructuring Steering Committee, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 36)
  November 9, 1992. Two drafts of minutes; memos
- Restructuring Steering Committee, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 37)
  November 13, 1992. Memo from Harry Lampman to Don Mesibov and Pat Flynn re relationship of NYSUT school restructuring project and NYSUIT services to locals implementing CR100.11; draft outline of training segment on project: the FORUM; draft working proposal from Don Mesibov and Pat Flynn to NYSUT School Restructuring Project Steering Committee, November 6; memo re project priorities, November 11; draft minutes of October 6 meeting
- Restructuring Steering Committee, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 38)
  October 6, 1992. Draft minutes of October 6 and September 9 meetings; restructuring project status report
- Restructuring Steering Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 39)
  April 15, 1992. Agenda; notes from project steering committee meeting of April 15, 1992; handwritten notes re Effective Teaching Program, for discussion only; draft proposal for summer conference; project status report by district
- Restructuring Steering Committee, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 40)
  March 9, 1992. Conference evaluation form responses, by district
- Restructuring – Don Mesibov, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 41)
  January 10, 1992. Agenda for eleventh annual statewide conference on inservice education, "Professional Development: Making the Compact Work," January 10-12, 1992, coordinated by NY State Education Department and NYSUT; minutes of December 18, 1991, meeting; memo from Mesibov outlining goals for upcoming meeting, January 13, 1992
- Restructuring Meeting, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 42)
  June 12-13, 1991. Script for video, "Authentic Work and How to Assess It"; outline re personnel needed for restructuring project; paper, "Implementation Strategies to Overcome the Barriers to Learning and Teaching"; memo from Don Mesibov to Pat Flynn with marked-up joint working document re restructuring
- Restructuring Meeting, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 43)
  December 18, 1991. Agenda; list of attendees; shared decision making evaluation report for Canton Central School District
- Restructuring – Grand Island Conference, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  February 28 - March 1, 1992. Training materials, "Working Together for Tomorrow," for Grand Island, Niagara Falls, and Royalton-Hartland school districts; related memos re Effective Teaching Program
- Restructuring Project, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  AFT training document, "The Restructuring Handbook," May 1991; agenda and discussion materials for April 30 meeting
- Support Team, 1991-1993 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  Memo from Don Mesibov re resources needed to make the program work, November 26, 1991; summary of January 29, 1992, meeting; memo re needs assessment
- Restructuring – Project Training, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  December 3-4, 1992. Memo to Pat Flynn from Harry Lampman commending him for success of training program, requesting meeting to discuss reordering workload to accommodate priorities; consultant/trainer's guide; other workbooks, reports, and memos
- Restructuring – Training Material, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 5)